Good afternoon everyone
大家下午好
So I apologize I have to I'm going to sit mostly through this lecture
抱歉，我今天可能要坐着完成这个讲座
I managed to do something to my knee yesterday
昨天我的膝盖出了点问题
And I'm having trouble moving around very much
所以现在不便过多走动
But today what we're going to talk about is input/output
今天我们要讨论的是输入/输出
What it looks like from the programmers' perspective
从程序员的角度来讨论它是什么样的
And this is a you've already learned sort of a lot of the standard Unix libraries for like printf and scanf
大家对于许多标准的 Unix 库已经有所了解，比如 printf 和 scanf
And those routines and we'll talk about them a little but
还有其他例程等等，我们会稍微谈谈它们
What will first talk about is actually lower level I/O
首先要谈的是底层 I/O
Stuff that is directly interfacing to the operating system
直接对接操作系统的 I/O
And this is what you're going to need to learn about
这就是大家需要了解的内容
Partly some of this material you're going to need for the next lab that comes out at midnight tonight the Shell Lab
其中有些材料是下次实验中需要用到的，即今晚午夜发布的 Shell Lab 实验
And you'll need to
而且大家需要
Also you'll be revisiting this at several other labs along the course including the final lab,the the Web Proxy Lab
本门课程的其他几个实验中也需要用到本节课的内容，包括最后的 Web Proxy Lab 实验
So this is sort of where we're really digging down deeply into this type of programming you do
我们需要对此进行深入研究
If you're writing system software things that are very just barely above the operating system level
因为这有助于大家编写层级略高于操作系统的系统软件
And I know for myself learning this material I actually learned this material from 213
我自己也从 213 学过这些材料
My co-author David O'Halloran is the one who knew this stuff already
我的合著者 David O'Halloran 是了解这些的人
He wrote that part of the book
他编写了书中的相关部分
I learned it by reading the book just like you are
我也是像大家一样，通过读这本书才学到的
But I found it actually very useful to know a variety of different other situations
但我发现同时去了解我所处的许多其他情形
I've been in in the meantime
实际上很有用
This is quite a few years ago and so I think it's worth understanding
这是好几年前的事了。总之，我认为该内容值得我们去了解
And I'll also mention this kind of material usually is taught
这种材料通常以授课的方式呈现
You don't really see it covered in most books
因为大多数书籍中不会涉及这部分内容
Except for ones that are really oriented toward system programmers and are fairly arcane
除非是真正面向系统程序员编写的书籍，但这些书籍读起来相当深奥
Or you try and learn it by reading man pages
大家可能也会在手册页中看到对相关内容的阐释
And that's a fairly cryptic way to try and understand sort of a set of abstractions provided by an API
但这不过是对 API 中各种抽象现象的含糊描述罢了
So I hope you'll find this useful
所以我希望大家会发现本节课很有用
So what we'll talk about then is that what I mentioned this low-level I/O that
言归正传，我们今天要讨论的是我之前提到的底层 I/O
I supported by Unix and other related operating systems
我用 Unix 和其他相关的操作系统来支持这种底层 I/O
And then a package called RIO which stands to robust I/O
然后我们会讨论用来对 I/O 进行维稳加固的软件包 RIO
And you will actually not be using this package until the last lab for the course the proxy lab
虽然大家只有在最后的 Proxy Lab 实验中才会用到它
At which time you'll use it a lot
而且是经常用到它
But it's worth looking at and partly
但仍然值得我们在本节课中讨论，部分原因是
It's in the book it's well documented in the book
本书对其进行了很好的讲解
And if you really want to understand how software works or a system works
如果大家真的想了解软件或系统的工作原理
The best thing you can do is if you...if there's good quality source code to look at and study
最好的方式就是看并学习优质的源代码
You can learn a lot from doing that
大家可以从中学到很多东西
And I really recommend for that chapter in the book that you go ahead and study all of the code
我真心建议大家去阅读本书中的那一章，研究构成 RIO 的所有代码
That makes up RIO. It's not a huge amount
代码不会很多
And just get an appreciation for the subtleties involved in
只需要去体会在处理不同情形时的微妙之处即可
How you deal with errors, how you deal with exceptional conditions and things like that
包括如何处理错误、如何异常情况等等
And then we'll talk some about how files are represented the sort of various data structures behind files
然后我们将讨论文件的表述方式，即文件背后的各种数据结构
How they support standard I/O and I/O redirection in Unix
它们如何在 Unix 中支持标准 I/O 和 I/O 重定向
And we'll also talk about the so-called buffered I/O
我们还将讨论所谓的缓冲 I/O
The I/O that you're more familiar with in C when you use printf and scanf
它常见于 C 语言中的 printf 和 scanf 函数
So Unix actually has a much simpler and more unified view of I/O than any other operating system and it's
Unix 实际上拥有所有操纵系统中最简单、最统一的 I/O 视图
One of the nice design features of it
它的其中一个设计优点是
Is that a lot of abstractions are built into the notion of a file
将许多抽象的事务嵌入文件的概念中
And a file is really just a sequence of bytes
而文件实际上只是一个字节序列
And in Unix does not distinguish between different classes of files unlike, say windows or earlier versions the macintosh operating system
在 Unix 中不区分不同类别的文件，这与 Windows 或早期版本的 macintosh 操作系统不同
It just thinks them as bytes
Unix 只是把文件看作字节
And the operating system level has essentially no understanding of a more detailed structure inside of a file
操作系统层级基本上不了解文件内部的详细结构
And one of the things it does is a file is normally originally thought of as
通常文件最初被视作
Something that stored on say a disk drive or some other external storage device
存储在磁盘驱动器或其他外部存储设备上的某个东西
And that you open you read it or write it you close it
通过打开、读写、关闭
Those sort of standard operations
等等这样一系列的标准操作来执行
But Unix also use the notion of a file to represent many other different  things including for example the devices
但 Unix 也会用文件的概念来表示许多其他不同的东西，例如
That are the I/O devices that are connected to a particular machine the TTY stands for teletype
连接到特定机器上的 I/O 设备。譬如 TTY 代表电传打字机
Which is an antique terminology for how people used to actually interface typewriters to computers
这是一种古老的术语，过去计算机界面中常常用此来表示打字机
The other thing that are viewed as like files are the network connections what are known as sockets
另一个被看作文件的是网络连接，即套接字
And when you do communication over the Internet
当跨互联网进行通信时
You do it by you send a message by writing to a socket
我们通过调用套接字来发送消息
And you accept incoming communication by reading from a socket
并通过读取套接字中的内容来接收消息
And so the same low-level API is the same
对于底层 API 来说也是如此
Whether you're reading or writing files on your disk drive or sending packets over the internet
无论是在磁盘驱动器上读文件还是写文件，还是通过互联网发送数据包
So the core operations then associated with files of course are opening and closing them and reading and writing them
与文件相关的核心操作是打开和关闭以及读和写
The other sort of attribute that's associated with most but not all files
与大多数但不是所有文件相关联的另一种属性是
Is what's called the file position so if again if you imagine
「文件位置」。大家设想一下：
When you're reading from a file you don't want to always start at the beginning every time you do a read
当从文件中读取数据时，没有人希望每次读取总是从头开始
You you read some data and then you read some more data
而是希望可以接着上次结束的地方继续读取
And so that's a track by a file position which is just a counter
这时候便会用到文件位置的追踪，文件位置只是一种计数器
That says how many bytes have been written read from this file so far
标记到目前为止已从该文件中读取了多少字节
So that I know where to go
这样一来便知道接下来要从哪里开始
You can actually even alter that value with a various classes operation called seeking
实际上，你甚至可以使用 seek 操作来改变该数值
Which is just a way of changing the file pointer the position pointer
这只是一种改变文件位置指针的方法
Now that doesn't work too well if your input is a terminal
该方法不太适用于输入是终端的情形
Where you can't move,you can't sort of back up and have recover data
因为该情形下你无法移动，无法备份和恢复
That was presented to it earlier or jump ahead and start accepting data that hasn't been typed yet
之前已经提交过的数据，而且也无法提前接收还未输入的数据
So there's some kinds of files have a file position and seeking
所以有些文件有文件位置和搜索
And others don't similar to a network socket
另一些文件则没有，类似于网络套接字
You can't jump a socket for it in time you can only read or write the particular packets as they come in
你无法在时间上进行跳转，只能在特定数据包进入时对其进行读或写操作
But in general think of it then as the file position
总的来说，我们把它看作文件位置
As part of the data associated with an open file
看作与打开的文件相关联的数据的一部分
That tells me how far along in this file have I read or written
借此获悉目前文件读取或写入的进程
And then again the files are because there's all these different things they're sort of unified in this file abstraction
这一抽象的概念将形形色色的文件统一起来
But obviously these differences
但显然文件与文件之间存在差异
And different attributes to them and so
和不同的属性
There's sort of many different categories and subcategories
因此文件分属许多不同的大类和子类
But the ones we'll think about are regular files just think of things that are on a disk drive
但是我们今天只考虑磁盘驱动器上的普通文件
Directories which is a...directory is considered a type of file meaning the data that's in there is just enough as a file
目录被视为一种文件，意味着其中的数据仅足够作为文件
But of course it's a special kind of file and that it actually does have an interpretation
但当然这是一种特殊的文件
That entries in that file describe the locations and attributes of other files
此类文件中的条目描述了其他文件的位置和属性
And then as I mentioned the term socket is a connection to a network
还有我之前提到的作为网络连接的套接字
And it's both for sending and for receiving messages over the network
其作用是发送和接收网络消息
There's other files that we won't really talk about
有一些文件我们今天不会讨论到
For example when you pipe,when you from one application to another
例如在两两应用程序之间传送数据时会用到的通道文件
That's both the output of the first program and the input of the second are special types of files called pipes
通道文件也是一类特殊文件，既是前一个程序的输出，也是后一个程序的输入
And they're handled by writing is putting something into the pipe and reading is to take something out of that pipe
处理方式有写——在其中放入数据；和读——从其中取出数据
A similar something called a symbolic link which is just a way that
再如符号链接，通过这类文件
You can have multiple names for a file
一个文件可以有多个名称
And pointers to a file that aren't really without having to make separate copies of a file
多个指针，而不需要单独创建文件副本
And then other special types of devices
还有其他特殊类型的设备
So we won't really will only consider for the first three types of files
总之，我们只会考虑前三种文件
And in fact for today mostly the first two
事实上今天主要是前两种
So the idea of a file then is it just contains arbitrary data
在这个背景下，文件只包含任意数据
And the operating system really for regular file doesn't try to get into the details of what's inside that file
用于普通文件的操作系统不会试图了解文件内部的具体结构
And there's some class of applications that will distinguish between a text file and a binary file
有一类应用程序会区分文本文件和二进制文件
Not really at the operating system level but more higher levels
不一定是在操作系统层级，也可能在更高层级
And the main difference with that is that a text file should only have the standard characters of ASCII
二者的主要区别在于文本文件应该只包含标准的 ASCII 字符
Or another class would be various encodings that allow you to do encodings of non-English alphabets
或者是各种可以对非英语字母进行编码的编码
And binary files would be things like an image or actual object code or a video or audio file or something
二进制文件是图像或实际目标代码、视频或音频文件
That it's the...within that code there's a sequence of bytes that are encoding numbers in some form directly
在代码中包含一个字节序列直接以某种形式编码数字
And then the main thing about a text file is that there's certain functions that
文本文件的主要特征是
Distinguish a newline character meaning the end of a line of text
能够区分代表文本行结束的新行符
And you already learned about that character it's got the code of a 0xa as a byte code
大家对于新行符已经有所了解，该字符以 0xa 作为字节代码
And that became one of the forbidden codes of your attacks
它是攻击的禁用代码之一
Because it would be interpreted as a newline by the function gets
因为 gets 函数会将其解释为新行
Just to mention that
顺便提一下
This is one place when you're transferring files between say a Windows machine and a Linux or a MAC
当你在 Windows 和 Linux 或 MAC 之间传输文件时
One of the things if it's a text file that has to be changed is
如果传输的文件是文本文件，需要注意的一点是
That two classes of systems have different ways of interpreting of encoding when is the end of a line
这两种系统对文本行何时结束有不同的编码和解释方式
And in a Linux or MAC file it's just this character code 0xa
在 Linux 或 MAC 文件中，仅使用 0xa 字符代码
Which stands for line feed
表示换行
Whereas the Windows files finish with a two-character end of line
但是在 Windows 文件中，文本行的结束需要由两个字符表示：
Carriage return and line feed
回车加换行
And I show you this picture of an object that you've probably only seen in museums
本图中的物品大家可能只在博物馆中看到过
But it's a typewriter and just to tell you what the heck is a carriage return and what's the line feed
这是一台打字机，这里只是为了向大家展示什么是回车、什么是换行
I thought you might like to in case you've never actually used an old-fashioned typewriter
我想大家可能从来没有用过老式打字机
Basically at the end of it on the left hand side of a typewriter is this bar
可以看到，打字机左侧有一个滚筒
And when you start typing along
当你开始打字时
This roller with your page on it sinks along
滚筒就会带着纸向左平移，印上铅字
And it comes to the end and then you want to get back to the beginning of the next line
当滚筒移动到末端时，需要回到下一行的开头
So you want to both do the carriage return
这时候既要回车
Which is this thing shove it to the right
把这个滚筒推到最右边
And you want to do a line feed you want the roller on it to go down to the next line
同时也要换行，让滚筒切换到下一行
So there's a knob here that you can twist by hand
这里有个旋钮，手动旋转这个旋钮就可以完成换行
But in general what you do is you type along and then you go slam
总的来说，你这样打呀打呀打，打到行尾再像这样「嗖」地把滚筒推到最右端
Like that and this lever both pushes the thing back and it rotates the
打字机里有个杠杆，它会把滚筒推回到行首，并把滚筒旋转
The roller by one line's words
一行文字的距离
So carriage return line feed is where that actually comes from in case you wonder
这就是回车换行的由来，仅供大家了解
And then a directory as I mentioned it's stored as a file
然后是目录，正如我之前提到过，目录被存储为一种文件
But it's a file that the operating system at least the file system part of the operating system actually interprets in very specific ways
但对于此类文件，操作系统或至少是操作系统中的文件系统的解析方式是非常独特的
And as you know within every directory there's two special files
正如大家所知，在每个目录中都含有两个特殊的文件
.(dot) and ..(dot dot) referring to the local file and its parent in the tree structure
「.」和「..」，分别表示当前目录自身和树型结构中当前目录的父目录
And so in most systems
在大部分系统中
Systems that I know of there's a sort of hierarchical organization to the files
在我所知道的大部分系统中，文件存在一种层次结构
We're not going to talk much about files...systems
我们不会对系统展开太多讨论
But there's a hierarchical organization
但是存在这么一种层次结构
And that's maintained as a series of files each being the directory
这种结构被作为一系列文件来维护，这里的每个文件都是目录
And the directory then is a pointer to its subdirectory which again are files
目录又是指向子目录的指针，子目录也是文件
And so what's referred to in Unix terminology
所以在 Unix 术语
And most other operating systems what's known as a path name is a way to navigate
以及大多数其他操作系统中路径名是一种导航方式
Through this hierarchy of files and identify one particular one
通过这种文件层次结构导向一个特定的文件
And so that all comes to say that the low-level Unix operations
底层的 Unix 操作
That use to implement this are to open a file to read it and write it and to close it
利用路径名对文件进行打开（open）、读（read）、写（write）和关闭（close）操作
And those literally those are the names of the functions
这些也就是函数的名称
So the open function then you give a pathname
在使用 open 函数时，你需要给出一个路径名
And remember pathnames can be absolute meaning that they start with a '/'
路径名可以是用“/”开头的绝对路径
And they go all the way down the hierarchy
沿着层次结构向下走
They can be relative to a particular whatever your current directory is where
也可以是相对于当前工作目录的路径名
And they can also be relative to a user if you use the tilde slash or tilde
你还可以用“~/”或“~”来指定相对于用户目录的路径名
Then that sort of a shortcut in this path name to get to particular users
这种方式会让你更快捷地到达特定的用户目录
So a pathname can be any of those forms when you open it,it just has to be some way that just like you specify
路径名可以采取上述任意一种形式，当你打开文件时
In other places that you tell where this particular file is you're trying to open
尤其当文件不在当前工作目录时，你必须明确指出它所在的位置
And so it's given a pathname and then
所以要给出一个路径名，然后
It's given a integer code that says what do you want to do when you open this file
还要给出一个整数代码，说明打开文件时你要执行的操作
In what form do you want to open it
你想以什么形式打开它
And that's specified by a series of constants that are already predefined when you include the appropriate file
这个整数代码是由一系列预先定义好的常量指定的，但是你要 include 相关文件
And you can...and those actually get bitwise
常量按位定义
Each of those is a one bit flag in some power of two position
每一个常量都是一个等于 2 的某个次幂的 1 位的标志量
Or it's a position one bit in a field somewhere
或者是位于某个字段的一个 1 位的标志量
And so you can logically or those together if you want multiple combinations
因此你可以通过逻辑“或”运算得到多种组合
So for example I can say read-only,I can say read and write
例如只读、读写
I can say append meaning don't
又如用 append 表示追加数据
If I'm opening it to write don't begin it the don't start writing at the beginning start writing it wherever the end of the file
意思是当打开文件进行写的操作时，不要从开头开始，而是从文件结束的地方开始
So all those can be done and this is described in the book
所有这些都可以完成，这在书中也有所描述
By using the right set of names of constants and oring them together
通过使用正确的常量名称，并用“或”把他们联系起来
And that will return something that's called a file descriptor
返回一个文件描述符
And that's a very important idea that and one of the reasons why we're talking about this today
这是一个非常重要的想法，也是我们今天谈到它的原因之一
This is going to be very important in your lab
这在你的实验中非常重要
Is the notion of a file descriptor which is just a small integer
文件描述符只是一个小的整数
That lists which particular one of the open files
它指向当前打开的文件中某一个
That's being used by this particular program are you referring to
正在被某个程序使用的文件
And so it's a small number because these are a sign sequentially
它是一个比较小的数字，因为它按顺序编号
When you begin your program and you run
当你开始你的程序并运行时
And you're in fact limited on most machines to some
事实上，在大多数机器上
Some bounded number of open files you're allowed to have at any time
你在任何时候被允许打开的文件的数量是有限的
In fact if you go to...
事实上，如果你......
Let's see...
举个例子
If you're on a machine and you type in limits
如果你在机器上输入 limit
You'll see there that entry called descriptors
你会看到一个名为描述符的条目
1024 says that you can't have more than 1024 files open at any given time
1024 表示你在任何时候能够打开的文件的数量不超过 1024 个
And in fact if you've got 1024 files open
事实上，如果你打开了 1024 个文件
It's a chance you're doing something really seriously wrong
说明你犯了一个很严重的错误
Being that you haven't been closing the files you should be closing
那就是你没有关闭本应关闭的文件
And all the system calls including these always have return code
包括这些在内的所有系统调用总是有返回值
And the return codes vary sometimes a negative number is an error sometimes a zero is an error
返回值涵义不总是相同，有时候负数表示错误，有时候零表示错误
Now they're all different and all confusing and all inscrutable
由于它们都是不同的、令人困惑的、令人费解的
So you have to look at the documentation for every single one of those functions
你必须查看每一个函数的文档
And one of the rules we're going to hammer away at in this course
本节课中我们会反复强调的其中一条规则是
Is every time you make a system call you should check the return code
每次进行系统调用时都应该检查返回值
To see if there's an error and then do some appropriate way of handling the error
看看是否存在错误，并采取一些适当的方法来处理错误
That's just a practice it's a pain in the butt
这是一个惯例，但比较烦人
It makes your code look like a rat's nest of conditionals
因为这样做会让你的代码看起来像老鼠窝
You really would rather not because often there's an error you
你倾向于不这样做，因为当出现错误时
Deciding what you're going to do when there's an error is harder than
此时决定你要做什么更难
Then figuring just ignoring it all together
不如直接忽略
And so there's a lot of code out there
在代码面前
Where people just cross their fingers and hope there's never errors in their system calls
人们只能祈祷并希望系统调用永远不出错
But we're going to really push on you hard to say every time you make a system call check the return code
尽管如此，我们还是要强调每次进行系统调用时务必检查返回值
And do something if it's not right
如果存在错误，就采取措施加以解决
And so the open will return a number so that it's an int that it returns
执行打开操作会返回一个整数值
But if it's a negative number that means it couldn't open the file
如果返回值为负，则意味着该操作无法打开文件
For example the file doesn't exist or you're trying to open it in a mode
原因可能是该文件不存在或者你试图
That you're not authorized to open it in
在未经授权的模式下打开它
So there's three particular file descriptors associated with every single process that runs
每运行一个进程都会涉及到三个特定的文件描述符
One is standard input the other standard output the third is standard error
分别是标准输入、标准输出和标准错误
And they always have a file descriptor number 0,1,2
它们始终对应文件描述符编号 0、1、2
So that you shouldn't really refer to them by their file descriptor numbers
但你并不能通过相应的编号去引用它们
Even though you actually can reliably depend on those values
虽然实际上你确实能够依赖这些数值
Same way if you want to close a file
关闭文件也是一样
Also open you see you give a pathname and a one bit a one integer field
打开文件时，你需要给出一个路径名以及一个整数字段
That gives these flags say something about the modes in which you want to open it
表明你想在什么样的模式下打开该文件等
To close a file you just say close and you give the file descriptor number not the name of the file
关闭文件时，你只需要调用关闭函数，然后指出文件描述符的编号而不是文件名
And it returns a return code too
该操作也会返回一个返回值
So you might say now why in the world could you ever get an error closing a file it's open
这里你可能会想世界上难道还存在关闭打开的文件时报错的情况么
And the answers that actually can happen
答案是肯定的
In particular we'll see when we have multi-threaded programs
特别是在多线程程序中
Where it's possible to have to essentially two programs running at the same time sharing their data structures and
可能有两个程序同时运行，共享数据结构
Interacting with each other sharing their memory
互相交流，共享内存
It's a very important kind of programming and one that you can really make bad horrible mistakes in
这是一种非常重要的编程方式，也是你可能犯下可怕错误的一种
And one of the bad horrible mistakes is if you try to close a file that's already been closed
其中一个错误就是尝试关闭一个已经关闭的文件
It'll be an error and that can happen if there's two different parts of your program running
这个错误在程序的两个不同部分同时运行时就可能发生
And each of them tries to close the file
两个部分都试图去关闭同一个文件
So in the book and in this code you'll see
在本书和本段代码中
We introduced some error handling routines one of which is called perror
我们介绍了一些错误处理例程，其中一个我们称之为 perror
And all it does is print some not whatever message you want to print
它所做的只是打印一些而不是你想打印的任何消息
And then it exits the program
然后退出程序
Or no I guess it doesn't that I'll mention in a little while
不对，好像不是这样，稍后我会再提到
It just prints an error message
它只打印一条显示错误的消息
But the point is even something as mundane as closing a file you should be checking the return code
重点是即便是执行关闭文件这样枯燥的操作，你也应该检查返回值
Okay so this is the function that reads
现在我们来看读入函数
At this low level is called read
在底层操作中这个函数就叫 read
And it's given a file descriptor
会给它分配一个文件描述符
You provided a pointer to a buffer
你需要提供一个指向缓冲区的指针
That's you've had to allocate either statically or via malloc
缓冲区可以通过静态分配或通过 malloc 分配
And you also specify how long that buffer is  so that it can't overflow that buffer
并且你还需要指定缓冲区的长度，避免溢出
And read,just means read as many bytes as you feel like
read 的意思是你想读多少就读多少
But no more than the number I tell you to
但不能超过我规定的字节数
Which sounds like a weird statement
这听起来像一个奇怪的声明
What do you mean what you feel like
什么叫想读多少就读多少
Well it has to read at least one byte so if for example it's
它必须至少读入一个字节，如果它是
A standard input it will hang there and wait until
一个标准输入，它将挂起并等待，直到
Actually with standard input it will wait until you've typed in a string and hit the return
你输入一个字符串，然后点击回车
And it will then read at least some fraction of that into the program
它就会将该字符串的至少一部分内容读入程序中
If it's a network connection again
同样地，如果它是一个网络连接
The read will just wait it will hang until something arrives
它也将挂起并等待，直到
On that particular network connection and then read in some number of bytes
新的内容进入该网络连接，它又会读入一定数量的字节
That have been sent to it and I'm being vague by saying some number
在这里，我说的“一定数量”是泛指
Because the truth is that there's no guarantee it will read any fixed number of bytes
因为在实际情况下，它读入的字节数不是固定的
It will read at least one
它至少读入一个字节
And it won't read any more than that buffer is
最多读入等于缓冲区长度的字节数
But the number between that might be variable
但介于二者之间的字节数是不一定的
And so when it reads less than that the number of maximum number bytes you specify
所以当它读入的字节数小于你指定的最大值时
That's called a short read
这种情况就被称为短读
And that can and does happen and you have to write your code
这种情况有可能也确实会发生，所以在写代码的时候
Expecting it and we'll talk about that a little bit
要考虑到这种情况，对此我们将展开一些讨论
Oh and so again and by read returns in a signed number
read 函数会返回一个有符号的数字
Actually of data type ssize_t like s s i z e underscore t
对于 ssize_t 这种数据类型
Which is typically a long int
这个数字通常是一个有符号的长整数
So a potentially negative number in it,that number is if it says zero
所以它有可能是负数，如果返回 0
It means that it's hit it's detected the end of the file
表示检测到 EOF
That you've run to the end of the stored file that the network connection has been closed or something has happened
你已经运行到所存文件的末尾或网络连接已经关闭等
If it's positive then that's the number of bytes that were read
如果返回一个正数，该正数则表示已经读取的字节数
And if it's negative it's an error code
如果返回一个负数，则表示出错
So as I mentioned if it reads fewer than the number of bytes you specify
正如我之前提到的，如果读入的字节数少于你指定的最长字节数
That's referred to as a short count and I'll talk about why that would occur
这种情况被称为不足值，我稍后会解释为什么会这样
Writing is sort of the same idea that you provide a file descriptor you provide a buffer
写文件和读文件差不多，都需要提供一个文件描述符、一个缓冲区
Where the the data that you want to write out is stored
缓冲区用于存储你要写出的数据
And you give up how many bytes long do you want your write to be
你不能想写多长就写多长
And it will write some number of bytes to the output at least one and no more than n bytes
它会输出你写的部分字节，最少 1 个，最多 n 个
But it might not be all of them which is kind of weird because you said
但不一定写多少输出多少，这可能有点奇怪，因为你说
I want to write this, I want to send it to a file, I want to send it over the internet
我想写这个，我想把它发送到一个文件，我想通过互联网发送它
But it can potentially not send them all
但可能无法全部发送
And well we'll talk about that a little bit
这种情况被称为短写
So again that's called a short write
这个我们稍后会再谈一谈
And similarly it will return the number of bytes that were written
类似地，写也会返回写出的字节数
And so if it's less than zero that's an error code
如果小于 0，则表示出错
So just to give you a really simple example of this in action
下面我们来看一个简单的例子
This code does what you call echoing meaning that you type in something and it will print it out
这段代码会把你输入的内容一一打印出来
And it does it in the most mundane way possible
用一种最机械的方式
By reading specifying a single byte reads and a single byte writes
通过指定每读入一个字节，便写出一个字节
So you remember I told you read will read at least one byte, but no more than the number you've told it
我之前说过执行读入操作时至少会读入 1 个字节，但不超过你指定的字节数
So when you give it one, it means it will read exactly one byte
因此，当你指定 1 个字节数时，这意味着它将只读取 1 个字节
And similarly with write if you say write one byte that's guaranteed to happen
同理，执行写出操作时，如果你指定的字节数为 1，那么它肯定会写出 1 个字节
And so this is really really bad code
这其实是一段非常糟糕的代码
In the sense that call to read or to write
从读写调用的角度来说
The system level call is a relatively expensive call
系统级调用的开销是很大的
It means kicking your whole operation up to the operating system doing what's called a context switch
这意味着将你的整个操作抛给操作系统，执行所谓的上下文切换
Meaning it will go into the kernel of the system invoke operating system functions
为此，它将进入系统内核，调用操作系统的功能
Do whatever the read or write tells it to do come back out switch back to your job
按指令完成读或写操作，再跳出来切回到先前的工作
And that will typically take maybe 20,000 to 40,000 clock cycles
这个过程通常需要 20,000 到 40,000 个时钟周期
Which you know a clock cycle nowadays is less than a nanosecond so you say
现在 1 个时钟周期不到 1 纳秒，所以你可能会说
Yeah it's a you're talking
20,000 到 40,000 个时钟周期
Maybe 10 microseconds what's the big deal there
才不过 10 微秒，没什么大不了
But that'll add up if you start sending long files out over
但如果发送的是长文件，时间消耗不容小觑
You know millions of bytes if you start sending them a one byte at a time
例如，你要发送一个数百万字节的文件，如果你每次发送 1 个字节
You'll spend most of that time sitting in the operating system going crazy
你的大部分时间将是坐在操作系统前等待，这会让你抓狂
So this is not a good idea but it does work and that's actually a easy mistake
所以这不是一个好主意，但确实有效
You can make as a programmer is to not use it is to use the low level writing and reading
实际上，像这样使用底层读写是程序员容易犯的一个错误
And the program will function fine it's just it will be really really slow
程序运行良好，只是它真的很慢
But just to give you a demo of this idea of
我来给大家做个演示
Calls to the operating system
便于大家理解操作系统调用的概念
There's a pretty cool...
有一个很酷的……
So this program and this is on the web
先说一下这个程序
Linked off the webpage the code for this lecture
这个程序可以通过网页链接访问
So this one called cpstdin meaning copy standard input
程序名叫 cpstdin，意思是复制标准输入
Is just the code I showed you
它所采用的代码也就是我给你们看的那段代码
So if you type something it will just echo it back
如果你输入一些内容，它就会原样输出
So it's reading in...so it looks to you and to me
所以它在边读边写.……表面上看起来
Like it's
似乎它是
Reading a line of text and then echoing it back but what it's actually doing
读入一行文本后再原样写出，这是因为
Is again the interface to the terminal is one that it doesn't actually wake up this code until it gets a complete line
终端的接口决定它必须读入完整的一行后才会唤醒这段代码
But it's actually just printing these characters back one character at a time
但实际上它只是一次一个字符地将这些字符一一打印出来
And I can demo that by there's a pretty interesting
我给大家做个演示
Facility called tracing strace
这里有一个很有趣的追踪工具 strace
And what strace will do if you give it the name of a program
如果你给它提供一个程序的名称
Is it will detect every system call that you make
它会检测你的所有系统调用
Every basically call to the operating system functions
你在运行一个程序时
That you make when you run a program
对操作系统功能的几乎所有调用
And it will generally spew out this huge amount of inscrutable stuff that you don't really want to see
并且显示一大堆很复杂的内容，你看都不想看
I'll just show you this
给大家展示一下
It's telling you logging every single call and it's usually way too much stuff
它告诉你记录下的每一个调用，但全部显示的话太多了
So the more useful way to do this
所以更有用的一种方法是
Is to give it an argument that says I only want to watch some limited class of functions when this is running
定义一个参数，告诉它只看运行时的某一类功能
And so what I just want our calls to the write the low level output write
例如，我只想看对底层输出写的调用
And you'll see that what happens then is this string I typed in
接下来就会看到我键入的这个字符串
Turned into a series of 1 byte writes
变成了一系列 1 个字节的写
Calls to the low level write function
仅显示对底层写功能的调用
And of course same way I could show you the reads and writes
用同样的方式也可以显示对读写的调用
Let's try that
我们来试试看
And it's all confused because I'm measuring this comes out on standard error
这看起来令人困惑，我估计可能是因为这是基于标准错误显示的
But on the terminal it's sort of interleaving standard error and standard out, so it's kind of messy to look at
但在终端上标准错误与标准输相互交替，所以看起来比较乱
But again you can see that it's taking my characters
但大家仍然可以看到我键入的字符
And it's reading 1 and writing 1 in this loop
被 1 个字节地读、1 个字节地写，循环往复
So let's see Ctrl-d to get out of it back to the code
Ctrl-d 退出，回到代码
So what's this short count business why would that occur
那么为什么会出现不足值
Well there's a couple of ones as I mentioned if you counter an end-of-file
我提到过如果你遇到文件结尾
You're not going to read in however many bytes you are given for the buffer
此时不论你设定的缓冲区有多少个字节，你都会停止读入
If you are reading text lines from a terminal
如果你正在从终端读取文本行
The terminal handler will just send a line
终端处理器每次只会发送一行文字
It's worth at a time with the newline character terminating it
遇到新行字符就会停止读入
If you're reading or writing a network packet
如果读或写的对象是网络数据包
The way...network packets work is that or messages
网络数据包与信息的处理方式类似
If you have a big long message it's broken into smaller chunks
如果你有一条很长的信息，它会被分割成多个数据块
Typically about a thousand bytes or so. [Question]
每一块通常约 1000 个字节。【请讲】
[student speaking]
[学生提问]
If you are trying to read from an end-of-file return 0
如果从文件结尾开始读取，则返回 0
Um is that a short count it's a really short count yes but it's not a negative
这种情况是不是不足值？是，它确实是不足值，但不会返回负值
Yes so as it says here if you encounter an end-of-file
是的，正如这里提到的遇到文件结尾的情况
It will actually there's two things actually it's a really good question
这里实际上有两步。这是一个非常好的问题
If you're like near the end of a file you have a hundred bytes left and you say read 200
如果你接近文件结尾，假设还剩 100 个字节，你命令读入 200 个字节
Your first call to read will come back and
你的第一次读入调用将
Get 100 character it would say 100 and it will get that number
读入 100 个字符并返回 100
And then you call again the second time and it will return zero
然后你再进行第二次调用，它将返回 0
And so that's how you actually detect the true end of file
这就是你实际检测到文件真实结尾的方式
As opposed to you know some other reason you might have gotten a short count is if that
这也是出现不足值的唯一原因
You actually get a read of 0 the only case you'll get that for is an end-of-file
如果你得到的返回值为 0，说明你到达文件结尾
So that's a good question thanks
你提了一个很好的问题，谢谢
So again if over the internet typically packets are around a thousand bytes
回到我们刚才讲的内容，通过互联网发送的数据包通常约为 1000 个字节
It's actually depends on where it's gone through what layers in the protocols it's gone through
实际长度取决于它要通过的是协议中的哪一层
But 1500 bytes is actually the standard what they call minimum transmission unit
但标准是 1500 个字节，这就是所谓的最小传输单元
So if you have a big long file it will come back in blocks like that
因此，如果你有一个又大又长的文件，它就会被分割成那样的数据块
And if you're trying to read into a larger buffer
如果你想将该文件读入一个较大的缓冲区
It will typically come back in chunks
它通常也会以数据块的形式读入
[Question]
【请讲】
[student speaking]
[学生提问]
No in other words you
不，没有标准的缓冲区大小
And again if you're writing code you shouldn't expect any number particularly it will be dependent on the implementation
换言之，你在写代码时不用考虑具体的字节数限制，它将取决于代码的实现
[student speaking]
[学生提问]
No because I'm only reading or writing one character at a time right
不，因为我每次只能读或写一个字符，对吗？
So I guess you're asking what if I like spend a week typing characters in a really long string and hit return
我想你问的是要是我喜欢花一周的时间键入一长串的字符串后再点击回车呢
I don't know if you try it let me know the answer
我不知道，你试过后请告诉我答案
But it won't cause an error but that part believe me they've really gone through that code a lot of times
它不会导致错误，但相信我：这段代码他们已经试过很多次
And gotten rid of all those lurking buffer overflow vulnerabilities in the code
也经历并克服了代码中存在的无数个缓冲区溢出漏洞
But we'll let you do it I don't actually know
但我本人没有亲自尝试过，也不反对你去尝试
But within the you should write your code again expecting short counts as a possibility
编写代码时应该考虑到可能出现不足值
And by the way that's one of the the headaches of using this low-level I/O is
顺便说一句，使用这种底层 I/O 的麻烦之一就是
Is dealing with short counts it's not it's often sort of a nuisance of an application level
处理不足值。这通常是一种应用程序级别的麻烦
So you don't you usually package this kind of low-level file I/O into other libraries that you're calling
因此你通常会将此类底层 I/O 文件打包到你正在调用的其他库中
It's only where we're demonstrating this is the sort of lowest level in the stack
只不过我们在堆栈的最底层加以展示而已
And writing also can give you a short count
写也会出现不足值
For example if you're sending packets over a network it will only send as many as is that packet can hold
例如：当你通过网络发送数据包时，它只会发送每个包可以容纳的字节数
And then return back to you and you have to keep pumping them out to send the different packets
然后返回给你，你必须不停把它们抽取出来逐包发送
And so usually when you write code that uses this goal of while you have to anticipate these short counts
因此，通常当你在编写使用 while 目标的代码时，你必须预测到不足值的产生
So professor O'Halloran wrote a package called RIO
对此，O'Halloran 教授写了一个名为 RIO 的软件包
And you'll...for now we'll just talk about what this package is
现在我们只谈谈这个软件包是什么
This is a package that you really going to want to use for the final lab for the course
该软件包非常适用于本课程的最终实验
And so for right now it's more of a high-level here's an example of code that uses low-level I/O
截至目前我们遇到的大部分都属于高级，现在我们要讲的是使用低级 I/O 的代码
And packages up in a way that makes it a little bit more palatable
只是进行了更好的封装，让人更容易接受
So RIO provides actually a number of different, two different
RIO 实际上提供了许多不同的
Well actually three
准确来说
Two different levels of interface to this file I/O
是两种不同级别的 I/O 文件接口
The lowest one is basically just a fairly small wrapper around
最低级的接口基本上只是一个相当小的封装
The the existing the I/O  reads and writes you saw
对你之前看到的现有 I/O 读和写的封装
That will handle the short count issue
以此解决不足值问题
And so when you say with RIO if you make a call to the readn function and you say some number of bytes
例如，如果你用 RIO 调用 readn 函数并指定某个字节数
Then that function will not return until it's read that number of bytes
则在读完该字节数之前函数不会返回
So better be careful that many bytes are there if it's a network socket or a file
在处理包含很多字节的网络套接字或文件时需要多加注意
Well because it will flag an error message
因为它将标记错误信息
If it's...will actually hang up if it's a network connection waiting to read the bytes
实际上，对于网络连接，它将挂起并等待
Or return an error if it hits an end of file what it's not expecting
如果出乎意料地读到文件结尾，则将返回错误
And similarly with writen is sort of a wrapper around the write function
类似地，writen 也是一种对 write 函数的封装
That will deal with...just loop until the short counts are taken care of
它会一直循环直到解决不足值问题
And then there is another class of of I/O that's called buffered I/O
此外还有另一类 I/O 即带缓冲的 I/O
And this is what you really want to use in practice
这类 I/O 在实践中经常用到
And what you mostly use with the standard Unix I/O functions
也最常与标准 Unix I/O 函数嵌套使用
Is that you want to within the the user code build up a little buffer of
其作用是在用户代码中建立一个小的缓冲区
Of bytes that have either been read in but not yet consumed by the application program
用来存放已读入但尚未被应用程序使用的字节
Or you accumulate some number of bytes in your program
或用来存放程序中一些待输出的字节
Before it's actually shoved out into the file or out onto the network
未来你会将这部分字节放入文件或网络中
And there's two versions of that one is a text oriented line oriented I/O and the other is just a byte oriented I/O
它又分为两种，一种是文本导向的 I/O，另一种是字节导向的 I/O
So let's go through what the functions are and actually look at the code for them
那么让我们来具体看一看函数及相关的代码
So as I mentioned the ones called readn and writen are just very same
正如我所提到的那样，readn 和 whiten
They have the same general semantics as the read and write
它们的语义与 read 和 write 大体相同
But they deal with the short count issue
但他们处理的是不足值问题
So let's actually take a look at readn
让我们先来看一看 readn
So again readn is given a file descriptor
使用 readn 函数也需要指定一个文件描述符
A destination buffer
一个目标缓冲区
And a indication of how many characters
以及字符数
How many bytes it's supposed to read and it's supposed to
这里的字符数指的是它应该读取的字节数以及
It's supposed to return...I guess it will return either a negative number if there's an error
它应该返回的返回值...我想如果出错，返回负值
0 if it's at an end of file
如果遇到文件末尾 EOF，返回 0
Or the number of bytes read
或者读取的字节数
So I guess I was a little bit I should have been more careful
我想我...我应该更小心一点
If it hits an end of file partway through it will return a short count
如果它在中途遇到 EOF，它将返回不足值
But that's the only case it won't return a short count
但那是唯一返回不足值的情况。在其他情况下，
If there really it could have read more bytes
如果它还可以继续读，就不会返回不足值
So the main loop here you see is it keeps calling read over and over again until it's happy
所以可以看到这里的一个主要循环是它会不停调用 read
Ah one way it can be happy as if it's read as many bytes
直到读的字节数
As it was supposed to write read in the first place
等于一开始指定要读的字节数
The other is that if it hits an error code
另外，如果它遇到出错代码
And you'll notice that
你会注意到
Oh and that there's some subtlety of tracking which type of error that is
虽然对出错类型的追踪比较微妙
But in general the common cases it will return the negative number indicating an error
但通常情况下，它会返回表示出错的负值
If the number read is zero
如果 nread 为 0
Then that indicated an end-of-file
则表示 EOF
And so what it will return is as many bytes as it's read
在这种情况下，它将返回已读的字节数
So return the short count
即返回不足值
And here it's just saying okay I've read this number of bytes and increment and decrement the right values
这里的意思是我已经读了这么多的字节数，通过 -= 和 += 更新相应变量
So the point is it will keep looping keep doing reads until it either gets the number of bytes it should
重点是它会不断循环不断执行读操作，直到读完应该读的字节数
It hits an error or it encounters an end-of-file
或出错或遇到 EOF
And you'll see it has it's checking for all these different error conditions for every call it makes
你们会看到每次调用它都会遍历所有不同的出错条件
So this code by the way is sort of typical that
顺便说一下，这段代码比较典型
It looks a little messy when you first look at it but if you sort of study it it all makes sense
乍看之下有点凌乱，但稍加研究会发现这一切都是有道理的
Um so now let's talk about buffered I/O and
现在我们来谈谈带缓冲的 I/O 以及
What buffered I/O is...this is a very important concept
带缓冲的 I/O 是什么......这是一个非常重要的概念
So it's part of the reason we want to show you the code for it
这也是向你们展示代码的原因之一
So the idea of buffered I/O is that...there's a buffer meaning just an
所谓带缓冲的 I/O 是指自带一个缓冲区
Array of byte characters array of bytes
用于存放一组字符字节
They're allocated and associated with this particular file
并且与特定的文件相关联
And the program if it's on a read what it will do is it will fill up
如果程序正在执行读操作，它将填满
This buffer if it will give a read with a much larger number
该缓冲区，读入大量的字节
With a large number basically the size of the actual
读入字节数的上限取决于
How much memory you've allocated for this buffer
分配给该缓冲区的实际内存大小
And the system will fill that up with up to that number of characters
系统将根据该大小填充不超过最大内存的字符数
And then when the user program wants to now look at this get some bytes
当用户程序想要提取一些字节时
It will first check do I already have some in the buffer that haven't been read yet
它将首先查看缓冲区中是否还有一些尚未读取的字节
And if so I'll just return those
如有，将返回这些字节
Ah and if not then I'll refill the buffer
如无，将重新填充缓冲区
So the idea of it is instead of every time going to the operating system
其中的想法是不用每次都进入操作系统
And asking for one character small number of characters
请求其提供一个字符或少量字符
They called the operating system says give me pretty much as many characters as you've got up to some limit
而是调用操作系统，请求其提供不超过某个上限的字符
And then I'll just go away and let the application program
然后离开，让应用程序
Sort of pull these out a couple bytes at a time
每次按需提取字节
But I won't bug the operating system to do it I being the RIO function
但我不会再打扰操作系统，“我”指 RIO 函数
And the way it does it is by just keeping a pointer that indicates
它的方式是通过指针来指示
What part of the the bytes
字节的哪一部分
That I've already brought in from the operating system call
已经通过调用操作系统引入
But the haven't been supplied yet to the application program
但尚未提供给应用程序
And so in this sort of larger picture of things if you imagine you're walking through a file
想象一下你正在穿过一个文件
At any given point in time this buffer will represent some a range of in that file
缓冲区代表在任何给定的时间点该文件中的某些区间
Where the green is the stuff that's already been read by the application program
绿色代表应用程序已经读过的部分
The pink is the stuff that's been read
粉红色代表
But from the operating system out of the file
已经通过操作系统从文件中读出
But not yet read by the application program
但应用程序还没读过的部分
And the way this is implemented once you think about it
实现的方式想一想
It's not too hard to do
其实并不难
Is that associated with every file connection then is a file descriptor
每个文件连接都有一个相关联的文件描述符
Account that tells you how many bytes
这个描述符会告诉你
There are that have not been read yet
还有多少字节没有读
A pointer to where this this changeover is
有一个指针，指向已读未读的分割点
And then the actual storage of the buffer itself
然后是缓冲区本身的实际存储空间
The characters allocated the bytes allocated to the buffer itself
即分配给缓冲区本身的字符字节
And so here's an example then of using RIO to do this echo that
这是一个使用 RIO 边读边写的例子
You first read a line,and reading a line means it will look for and stop at a line feed character
先读一行文本，所谓读一行是指读到遇到换行符为止
And writing it back out
再把读的文本写出来
And again if you do the demo...of this code
我们来演示一下这段代码
It's a little again you get...let me just trace writes 'cause it's a little hard to see the reads here hard to figure out with...
同样也会看到......我们只追踪写操作，因为要查看读操作有点困难
So you'll see that it's
可以看到它
Read the whole line and now it's done to at the operating system level
读完了一整行，读完后在操作系统层面
It's written just one chunk's worth one call to the operating system's write function
调用操作系统的 write 函数，调用一次写一块
Instead of a byte by byte
而不是逐字节地写
Okay so again I'm not going to go through all the code
我不打算讲所有的代码
But it's actually worth your while to do this
但确实值得一试
And by the way I've actually done some applications where I took the RIO code I want to add some features to it
顺便说一下，我实际上进行了一些尝试，因为我想在 RIO 代码的基础上添加一些功能
But it's a very useful starting point to be able to build your own customized routines
这对于构建自己的自定义例程来说是一个非常有用的起点
Okay so let's talk about some other parts of files
现在让我们来谈谈文件的其他部分
One is that associated with a file is what they call metadata
一个是与文件相关联的称之为元数据的事物
So the data are the actual contents of the file actual bytes inside that file
数据是指文件的实际内容文件中实际包含的字节
But there's a whole bunch of other stuff that's associated with the file
但是还有很多其他与文件相关联的事物
Information about what type of file it is
有关文件类型的信息
What protection read/write/execute protections it has
有关文件保护类型读/写/执行保护的信息
Some information about the ownership of that file
有关文件所有权的信息
What type it is and also the times associated with it
它是什么类型以及与之相关的时间
When was it created, when was it last accessed,when was it last modified
什么时候创建，最后一次访问是什么时候，最后一次修改是什么时候等等
So that's known as metadata and every file has that kind of information associated with it
这就是元数据，每个文件都有这种与之相关联的信息
And you can actually and it's in a data structure called a stat
这种信息存放在叫做 stat 的数据结构中
Data structure
stat 数据结构
And you can if you want to write code that then sort of probes the directory structure of a file system
如果你想编写代码来探测文件系统的目录结构，你可以
You can make a call to the stat function
你可以调用 stat 函数
And it's given the pathname of the file you want to stat
在函数中给出你想要 stat 的文件的路径名
And then a pointer to one of these stat data structures and then that
并给出指向其中一个 stat 数据结构的指针
Data structure will get filled in by the information for this particular file
文件的信息就会填入该指向的数据结构
And then you can test various attributes about that file
然后你便可以测试文件的各种属性
And see basically get the information
而且基本上可以获得
That's stored here
存在 stat 数据结构中的全部信息
And there's all these nasty compile time constants
还有这些讨厌的编译时常量
That you use or macros that you use to look at and examine these metadata
或宏，它们的作用是用来查看和检查这些元数据
So here's an example I will do it but
举一个例子
But it's a function called statcheck it's in the same directory
如果调用处于同一目录下的 statcheck 函数
And so if you check some file or typically say well it's a regular file
来检查某个文件，通常是某个普通文件
And yes you're allowed to read it
它会显示 yes，表示你可以读这个文件
But now if I chmod to eliminate set all the protections to zero
但如果我用 chmod 命令将所有保护设置为 0
It'll say no you can't read it now
它会显示 no，表示你现在不可以读这个文件
And so again that's just making use of this data here
这是关于如何使用这些数据的例子
So now this is the part that gets a lot more tricky
现在到更棘手的部分
Is how our files...how are all this information about file is actually represented by the programs
我们的文件是如何......所有关于文件的信息是如何在程序中表示的
[Question]
[请讲]
[Student speaking]
[学生提问]
Yes stat just ah...
好，stat 是......
I'll tell you one way you can find out what stat does
有一种方法可以找出 stat 的作用
If you say man 2 stat
在这里键入 man 2 stat
You'll get more than you want to know
你不仅会得到你的答案，还会学到更多
So in general you know if you say man stat
一般来说，如果键入 man stat
It'll give a Unix command that you can use to stat a file
它将为你提供可用于 stat 文件的 Unix 命令
So I can say stat
我还可以键入 stat
And it will print out some information about a file
它将打印出一些有关文件的信息
In this case my local directory let's see
在这种情况下，我的本地目录让我们看看
I can stat any file
我可以 stat 任何文件
Here and it will print out some cryptic information about it
它将打印出一些加密的相关信息
But if you say man 2 stat
但如果键入 man 2 stat
The Unix man pages are divided into different categories
由于 Unix 手册页分为不同的章节
And things that our system calls
而系统要调用的内容
Unix system library calls are typically in section 2 of the man pages
Unix 系统库要调用的内容通常位于手册页的第二章节
And so that will return information about it
所以键入 man 2 stat 将返回第二部分的相关内容
But the main point of it is stat is then a function that you call
总之 stat 是一个可供调用的函数
Where you give it a path name and a pointer to a buffer that you want it
给它指定一个路径名和一个指向缓冲区的指针
And it will then fill in the contents the buffer with the information about that particular file
它将把有关文件的信息
And the form that it fills it in is one of these data structures called a struct stat
以数据结构 struct stat 的形式填入缓冲区中
And that's pretty typical of a lot of these functions is that they have some predefined struct
这些函数的一个典型特征是它们有一些预定义的 struct
And if you want to get the...if you want to get information you pa...
如果你想获取这些信息
You allocate one of those struts you pass a pointer to it
你可以先分配一个 struct，再指定一个指向该 struct 的指针
And then the library function will fill in the details
库函数就会将具体信息填入该 struct
[T: Does that make sense] [S: Yeah] [T: Okay]
【明白了吗？】【明白了】【好】
Okay so now let's look at some of the internal data structures that
好的，现在让我们来看看一些内部数据结构
The operating system maintains regarding the files associated with a program
这些数据结构与程序中的文件相关，由操作系统维护
And this is a source of really nasty exam problems
大家请注意这是考试的难点
I'll just warn you, so you're going to want to read this part of the book carefully
你们一定要仔细阅读这部分内容
Study the practice problems look at the old exams
研究习题、看看历次的考题
‘Cause I can guarantee you're going to get some of these on the final that's a promise
我保证期末考试中肯定会出现原题
And they can be infinitely obscure so
这些题目可能会很难懂
We can we can torch you with these
但是你们可以从中得到启发
So that the main point is that associated with any executing process
对于任何执行进程
Which you can think of a process as a running program
在这里我们可以把进程想成一个正在运行的程序
Is a something called the descriptor table
每个进程都有与之相关的描述符表
And what that contains is
每一个打开文件的
For every open file that you have
描述符表都包含
It has a pointer to a data structure called
一个指向数据结构的指针
An entry in a table that's maintained by the operating system globally
该数据结构是文件表中的一个表项，由操作系统进行全局维护
Which describes each of the open files
它描述了每个打开文件
Actually each...every time a file is opened
实际上每打开一个文件
That allocates a record in this open file table
都会在该打开的文件表中分配一条记录
And so as I mentioned file descriptor 0, 1 and 2 have specific meanings
正如我之前提到的，文件描述符 0、1、2 有其特定的含义
And the other files are other ones that you've opened during the course of your program execution and have not yet closed
其他描述符指代程序执行过程中打开但尚未关闭的其他文件
So that's so each of these then is a reference to a particular open file
这些描述符每个都指代一个特定的打开文件
And it gives information about that file
它提供了文件的有关信息
And it also gives the position in the file that
它还给出了文件位置
Currently is that I told you every time you open a file there's
这个位置就是我之前提到的你每次打开一个文件
A for a regular file at least
一个普通文件
There's an associated position of where in the file was your last read or write
会有一个相关的位置指向你上一次读或写的结束位置
Or where would you be your next read or write
或者下一次读或写的起始位置
And so that's the file pause
这就是文件暂停的位置
And there's also a reference count which is used by the operating system to keep track of
描述符表还包含一个引用计数，操作系统用它来进行追踪
'Cause we'll see it's possible to have multiple processes sharing
因为可能会有多个进程共享
An entry in this open file table and
同一张打开的文件表的表项
It uses this reference count which is standard way of keeping track of memory allocation
所以使用引用计数来追踪内存分配，这是标准的做法
To know when it no longer needs that entry if when there's been enough
什么时候不再需要表项呢
When the file is no longer accessible and therefore this entry is not needed
当文件不再可供访问时，则不再需要表项
So for every one of your open files that will have an entry in this table
总之每个打开文件都会在文件表中有一个指向其的表项
And this table as I said is shared across the whole operating system
而这个文件表由整个操作系统共享
And then associated with every file is called a v-node
每个文件还有一个与之相关的 v-node
Which stands for virtual node
即虚拟节点
And this is where that contains the sort of information about this file
其中包含了文件的相关信息
In particular where it is stored this information that you can get from stat and things like that
特别是文件的存储位置以及从 stat 中能够获取的信息等等
How big it is and things like that
文件的大小等等
So that's for every file in the system actually has a v-node entry
实际上系统中的每个文件不论是否打开
Whether it's open or closed
都有其对应的 v-node 表表项
Now this can get complicated
这个解释起来可能会比较复杂
So for example if within a single program you call open twice on the same function
举个例子，如果你在某个程序中用同一个函数调用 open 两次
You'll actually get two different file descriptors
你会得到两个不同的文件描述符
And you'll be able to access that same file and have two different positions in it
你能够访问同一个文件并得到两个不同的文件位置
Then it makes sense if you imagine you're reading from a file
简单来说：想象你正在读一个文件
And you might want to read from two different positions in that file
你希望在同一个程序中从该文件的两个不同位置读取
Within the same program and you can do that that's perfectly legal
你可以这样做，这是完全合法的
You just call open twice and that will keep track of two different positions
你只需要调用两次 open，生成两个不同的文件位置
So the point is these file descriptors might be referring to the same file
总之这些文件描述符可能引用的是同一个文件
But they're actually at different positions within the file
但实际上它们的文件位置不同
And that can happen also if you've opened a file for both reading and for writing
此外，如果你打开一个文件进行读和写
And you're writing ahead and then reading characters bytes that have already been written
并且写在前读在后，也会发生这种情况
That makes sense
这就不难理解了
It's not such a good idea to have two different write
不建议对同一个文件
File opens that are writing simultaneously you can mess up the file pretty badly that way
两次调用 open 进行写操作，因为这样文件会变得很乱
But there's nothing in the operating system that prevents you from doing that
但是操作系统不会阻止你这样做
So it's not a good idea but it's a legal operation
虽然不建议这么做，但这是合法的操作
So that's the point is you have to distinguish at what level is sharing taking place and you see that
所以重点是你们必须识别共享发生在哪一个级别
If you have two different table entries sharing one file
如果有两个不同的表项共享一个文件
Then that what's different there is that you can be working at different file positions
则它们可能引用的是不同的文件位置
Similarly of course the more common thing is
当然更常见的是
You have two different open files and they're referring to different files
你有两个不同的打开文件，它们引用不同的文件
But now and this is where life gets exciting
现在有意思的地方来了
If you call fork you remember about fork that it spawns a child
如果你调用 fork，我讲过 fork 会生成一个子进程
But that child inherits a lot of information from its parent
子进程从父进程那里继承了很多信息
And one of the things it inherits
其中之一是
Is its descriptor table it gets a replica of that descriptor table
父进程的描述符表，子进程会获得该描述符表的副本
And so now both the parent and the child
所以父子进程
Have identical entries in their descriptor table
有相同的描述符表表项
And so they're sharing files
所以它们共享文件
But not at the file level but at the open file table
但不是在文件级别而是在打开文件表级别共享
And what that means is if the parent does a read
这意味着如果父进程进行读操作
It'll bump along the file position
它会沿文件位置前进
And if the child now does a read
如果此时子进程再进行读操作
It will see oh this from this new position
它将从这个新位置读起
So you can see why the exam problems get really interesting
可想而知为什么考题会变得非常有意思
That will keep track of all these different possibilities
因为会涵盖所有这些不同的可能性
And they'll do different things
以及不同的情况
And so...
所以.....
And then of course the parent or the child can start opening and closing their own files as well and that will get very messy
当然父进程或子进程可以打开和关闭它们自己的文件，但会变得非常混乱
And here's what you see the reason for having reference counts here that
这就是为什么这里会有引用计数
If you have a lot of forking going on
如果 fork 太多
Then you can create multiple pointers to this table entry
你可以创建多个指针指向此表项
And in order to really really close the file each of these has to call close
如果要真正关闭文件，每个进程都必须调用 close
Before the file is truly truly closed from an operating system perspective
才能从操作系统的角度真正关闭文件
So there's other fun things that make life interesting too and contribute to the exam problem possibilities
还有其他有趣的事情，它们让生活变得有趣，也增加了考题的可能性
One is called dup2
其中一个叫做 dup2
And the purpose of dup2 is to
其目的是
[Excuse me] duplicate an entry in the descriptor table
【不好意思】复制描述符表的表项
And the most common use of that is I/O redirection that either greater or less than sign to either
该函数最常见的用途是 I/O 重定向，用 > 或 < 符号
Redirect read the instead of from standard input from the file
将标准输入的读重定向到文件
Or instead of writing to standard output to write to a file
或者将标准输出的写重定向到文件
And the way the operating system actually implements that is shortly after starting the program
操作系统使用该函数的方式是在程序启动后不久
It will call dup2
调用 dup2
To make it so that the file descriptor 1 is not the standard output of the for this process
从而使文件描述符 1 不再是此进程的标准输出
But it's actually the original standard output
最初的标准输出
But it's actually a descriptor for the file that it's supposed to write
而是待写出文件的描述符
And same way if it's doing input redirection
输入重定向也同样如此
And but you can call dup2 yourself
但你也可以自己调用 dup2
And do these kind of things and there's actually good reasons for doing so
完成重定向，并且这样做很合理
So in particular imagine I open the file
举个例子，我先打开文件 A
And standard output points to the sort of normal thing
标准输出像往常一样指向此表项
And I open a new file I call it B
我再打开一个新的文件 B
And then I call dup2
接着调用 dup2
[Excuse me]
【不好意思】
And now what both file descriptor 1 and file descriptor 4 are sharing
现在文件描述符 1 和文件描述符 4 共享
This entry in the file table and you see the reference count of 2
此文件表表项，引用计数显示为 2
And so in order to really close it then
如果要真正关闭它
What would typically happen at this point is the this happens before
通常需要在它启动程序前
It starts your program you'd want to close file descriptor 4
关闭文件描述符 4
And in fact there's a lot of bugs you can make by not closing files
如果不关闭文件，可能会出现很多漏洞
It's easy to make mistakes when you have multiple entries in these tables
表项存在共享时很容易出错
[Yes] [Student speaking]
【请讲】 【学生提问】
No, if I call close this one it just decrements this reference count
不会，如果调用 close 函数关闭文件，只会减少引用计数
But this remains a valid entry here
但这仍然是一条有效的表项
[student speaking]
[学生提问]
Yes but dup2 will decrement the reference count of the original
是的，但是 dup2 会减少文件 A 的引用计数
So dup2 goes backwards from where you think it should
让我们回去再看看 dup2
So dup2 is the...
所以 dup2 是......
I want what I refer to for example file descriptor
例如
I want file descriptor 4 to become what I can use to and refer to with file descriptor 1 here
如果想用文件描述符 1 引用文件描述符 4
It will actually decrement the reference count
dup2 将先关闭 newfd 原先指向的文件，减少该文件的引用计数
Of this before it done does the copy
然后再进行复制操作
Otherwise it will create like an orphan in this table, right
如果不关，引用计数就不会为 0，内核就无法释放它，对吧
So anyways dup2 also is a powerful but dangerous mechanism
总之 dup2 是一个强大但危险的机制
So now finally let me just mention the much more common I/O that
最后我再提一下应用程序中
Application programs use
更常用的 I/O
Is what's known as the standard I/O and that's what's documented in K&R and
这就是标准 I/O，K&R 一书中对此作了相关说明
It's actually part of the the C standard
标准 I/O 实际上是标准 C 的一部分
All these different functions
包含不同的函数
And so the main feature it adds is sort of like what you saw with the RIO package it adds buffering
类似于 RIO 包，标准 I/O 函数都带有缓冲功能
So it doesn't have to do this low-level stuff
所以避免了很多低级操作
And it avoids all then some of the nastiness
也变得更简单了
And the way it works is what we've already seen it uses buffering to do the I/O
它用缓冲来进行 I/O 操作，工作原理我们之前已经讲过了
So just it is an example
例如
Here's some code that calls printf
这是一段调用 printf 的代码
One character at a time to print the word hello
打印单词 hello，一次打印一个字符
But if I run that and I strace it
我现在运行它并执行 strace
You see that there's only one system call to write
我们就会看到只有一个对 write 的系统调用
And it works the same way you saw with the RIO code
它的运作方式和 RIO 代码相同
It builds up a buffer and it's not until this call to fflush
它会创建一个缓冲区，先写到缓冲区，再调用 fflush
That forces the output to actually be a printed output
把写的内容打印输出
Usually that happens automatically actually if you printf a line feed it will flush it
通常如果 printf 换行符，它将自动 flush
So but that I think that call to fflush is probably redundant here
所以我认为在这里不调用 fflush 也可以
So and so that's the benefit, so buffered I/O is much more efficient
综上所述，带缓冲的 I/O 效率因为有缓冲的缘故
Because of the buffering
效率会更高
So as a result we've now seen three different types of I/O
这节课我们一共学了三种不同类型的 I/O
There's the low-level I/O called U...referred to as Unix I/O
一个是低级的 Unix I/O
You saw this package that was written specifically for the book and for the course called RIO
另一个是专门为本书及本课程编写的 RIO 包
And then there's a much larger
最后是由 Unix 标准库提供的更多、
And in fact richer set of I/O functions provided by the Unix standard library
更丰富的标准 I/O 函数
So you might ask a couple of questions one is why the heck did you write this when you've already got that
这里你们可能会有疑问，既然已经有了标准库提供的函数，为什么还要自己去写
If Unix provides buffered I/O why did you do it yourself
既然 Unix 提供带缓冲的 I/O，为什么还要自己建
And the reason is this stuff doesn't it works really well for
这是因为标准库提供的函数虽然非常适用于
The I/O you do to a terminal or to files
对终端或文件执行 I/O 操作
But it doesn't do very well with network connections
但不太适用于网络连接
It wasn't really designed for that and so it gets really messed up
它不是为网络连接设计的，所以不好用
And so the main reason you're going to find yourself using this is when you're starting to use network connections
因此 RIO 函数主要是用于网络连接
The other thing is these do not coexist very well buffered I/O with a RIO I/O
此外，带缓冲的 I/O 与 RIO I/O 不能很好地共存
Because they each maintain their own buffers and they don't know about each other
因为它们各自都有自己的缓冲区，彼此之间互不了解
And they get terribly confused
还会相互干扰
So you kind of have to pick one or the other with respect to any particular I/O connection
所以在对某个 I/O 连接进行操作时，你只能二选一
And don't try to mix and match them
切忌混用和匹配使用
So like I said Unix I/O then the low-level stuff from an application perspective
接下来看看每种 I/O 各自的优缺点。首先是低级的 I/O，从应用程序的角度
It's like really painful to use especially with short counts and error codes
它不是很好用，存在不足值、出错代码等
And and all that stuff
诸多缺陷
So in general you want to either write your own package or use some other package around it
所以一般来说需要自己编写程序包或者用其他程序包对它进行封装
And so as I said standard I/O it gives you printf and scanf and all these nice features
然后是标准 I/O，它提供了 printf、scanf等很多不错的功能
It's uniform it exists on all systems
它是统一的，所有系统中都有
It's reasonably standardized
而且很标准化
So in general then use the standard I/O for most year
所以标准 I/O 最常用于
Day-to-day uses of files
日常文件的使用
I'll use a raw I/O for low-level stuff like when you have to
我会用 Unix I/O 完成一些低级操作
And partly it turns out signals are not
比如编写信号处理程序
You shouldn't use standard I/O when you're writing signal handlers
此时不应使用标准 I/O
And then the RIO you're going to find useful for in particular for doing networking
RIO 非常适用于网络操作
One other thing that you should one bug that students do over and over again in this course
学生们在这门课程中常犯的一个错误是
Is they try to do a line oriented I/O on things that aren't lines
尝试对没有行概念的文件进行基于行的 I/O 操作
So like a jpeg image or something like that
比如 jpeg 格式的图片等
And the reason that's important is that these functions
主要是因为这些函数
Are treat the end of line character 0a is a very special character
在处理行尾字符 0a 这个特殊的字符时
They'll stop reading or something like that or if it's going between windows and Unix
会停止读入，或者如果是在 Windows 和 Unix 之间进行切换
It will actually change one from carriage return from line feed to carriage return line feed
会从换行符切成回车和换行符
Same way functions like strlen and strcpy will stop when they hit a null byte
同样地，strlen、strcpy 等函数在遇到空字节时会停止
And that's not what you want to do when these are network packets you're trying to send out
在发送网络数据包时，你可不想遇到这种情况
So be careful some of the functions you've used a lot and you're very familiar with
所以要谨慎，因为有时候你经常使用而且非常熟悉的一些功能
May be completely inappropriate for things where you're doing binary data
也许完全不适用于你当下的操作，比如二进制数据
Or you're communicating over networks and things like that
或网络通讯等等
So be sure you understand what you're doing when you start to use these kind of functions
所以在用这些函数前先弄清楚要做什么
So those who you really want to know this stuff
如果想更进一步了解
There's a fellow named Richard Stevens who unfortunately died
向大家推荐理查德史蒂文斯写的一套书
A while quite a while ago
史蒂文斯已经过世多年
But his books live on and there's various people have signed up to become co-authors with him in his absence
在他过世后，又有很多人成为这套书的合著者
And creating new editions of these books that used to date back way far
让这套经典著作得以延续至今，不断推出新版本
So and if you really want to know how this stuff works you want to be the ace programmer
所以如果你很想知道具体的运作原理，想成为一名王牌程序员
These books are the best you can get
这套书是你最好的资料
But I'll also warn you your bookshelf will become very heavy laden because there's
但我得告诉你们，这套书是个大部头
There's the volumes one two and three and then there's networking books and
有一、二、三卷，还有几本讲网络的
Stevens is like a encyclopedic reference
就像是一套百科全书
But they're excellent books if you really want to understand something  read Stevens
但这是一套优秀的书，如果你真的想深入研究，就去读史蒂文斯
And there's another book that is just specific to Linux that's fairly nice and somewhat it's very detailed
还有另一本专门针对 Linux 的书，这本书也相当不错、非常详细
But since it's only trying to deal with Linux it's a little bit less weird than trying to read Stevens
但因为它只针对 Linux，所以读起来比史蒂文斯的书更轻松
Because Stevens will say in this version of Unix it works this way in this version it works that way and blah blah blah
在史蒂文斯的书中，它会讲到在这个版本的 Unix 中是这样的，在另一个版本中又是那样的等等
And it's all different and it will drive you crazy
读起来让人抓狂
But Stevens is still it's an outstanding set of books
但这不失为一套出色的书籍
Ok so...
好......
This is an example and I'm not going to go through it
这只是一个例子，我不打算讲它
But these are the kind of things that we use to torture students that you
这是我们用来折磨学生的题目之一
Open some file descriptors and you do some dups and you do
打开一些文件描述符，然后做一些 dup
Some forks and so you end up with a real spaghetti for all the pointers
一些 fork，最终得到各种指针
What's shared and what's not shared and then you ask what will this print
一些共享，一些不共享，最后问打印结果是什么
And of course you'll have to trace through in great detail what's really going on
当然，你必须仔细追踪才能知道到底发生了什么
So those are in the book and I recommend you work on some of those
这些题目在书里都有，我建议你们去研究其中的一些
Ok that'll do us for today then
那么这节课就到此结束